Guide to the Joseph V. Charyk papers, 1957-1989 MS2137
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Conferences, symposiums, and seminars, 1961-1983; MS2137 Series 3; 2.5 Linear feet (Box 62, Box 61, Box 60)
  - University of Texas Seminar Monterey, California May 22, 1967, 11/21/1966-06/22/1967 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Alaska Broadcasters Association June 8 - 9, 1967 Fairbanks, Alaska, 03/16/1967-03/20/1967 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Great Lakes Conference of Public Utilities Commissioner The Greenbrier August 15, 1967, 03/30/1967-10/03/1967 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - IEEE Symposium September 22, 1967 Washington, DC, 07/11/1967-09/13/1967 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - 5th Anniversary Dinner 1968, 02/14/1968 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Brewster - Paumalu Visit January 1968, 01/18/1968-02/19/1968 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Presidents Round Table (AMA Presidents Association) Ft. Lauderdale, Florida February 5, 1968, 12/14/1968-04/10/1968 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Rice University (Baker College) Houston, Texas February 27, 1968, 11/02/1966-03/21/1968 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - International Communications Market Conference Department of Commerce 4/3/1968, 03/15/1968-05/17/1968 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Fidelity Mutual Life Insurance Company President's Club Meeting 3/25/1968, 07/27/1967-04/15/1968 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - International Aviation Club Washington, DC April 18, 1968, 04/18/1968-05/21/1968 (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Spring Yama Conference (NCIB) Seaview C.C., NJ April 19 - 21, 02/19/1968-05/03/1968 (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - International Aviation Conference Calgary, Canada May 23, 1968, 03/30/1968-10/29/1968 (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Senior Seminar in Foreign Policy Washington, DC May 18, 1968, 05/01/1968-06/13/1968 (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - National Academy of Sciences Washington, DC June 12, 1968, 04/12/1968-03/26/1969 (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - State Department Meeting International Educational and Cultural Act June 25, 1968, 11/14/1967-06/25/1968 (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - UN Conference on Outerspace [1/2] Vienna August 14 - 27, 1968, 11/1967-08/19/1968 (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - UN Conference on Outerspace [2/2] Vienna August 14 - 27, 1968, 08/04/1967-08/16/1968 (Box 61, Folder 21)
  - ITU Space Symposium Paris June 4, 1971, 10/27/1970-06/14/1971 (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - NY Society of Security Analysts NYC September 6, 1972, 02/23/1972-09/25/1972 (Box 61, Folder 23)
  - Canadian Earth Station Inaugural Lake Cowichan September 26, 1972, 09/13/1972-09/28/1972 (Box 61, Folder 24)
  - Today Show NYC October 5, 1972, 08/31/1972-10/07/1972 (Box 61, Folder 25)
  - Underwriter Information Meeting (AT&T Sale of Stock) NYC June 6, 1973, 10/18/1973-10/24/1973 (Box 61, Folder 26)
  - Association of Professional Engineers, Geologists & Geophysicians Alberta, Canada June 1, 1973, 10/11/1972-06/06/1973 (Box 61, Folder 27)
  - Council on Foreign Relations NYC November 7, 1973, 06/13/1973-11/30/1973 (Box 61, Folder 28)
  - AIAA Annual Meeting January 29, 1974 Washington, DC, 09/05/1973-12/04/1973 (Box 61, Folder 29)
  - AAAS Annual Meeting [1/2] San Francisco February 28, 1974, 01/08/1974-03/07/1974 (Box 61, Folder 30)
  - AAS Annual Meeting [2/2] San Francisco February 28, 1974, 10/04/1973-03/01/1974 (Box 61, Folder 31)
  - 34th ASEB Meeting Washington, DC October 8 - 9, 1974, 09/13/1974-10/10/1974 (Box 61, Folder 32)
  - Marconi Award Bologna, Italy October 14, 1974, 06/21/1974-10/23/1974 (Box 61, Folder 33)
  - IBM Forum '75 Meeting Los Angeles December 12, 1974, 06/01/1974-12/19/1974 (Box 61, Folder 34)
  - CalTech Alumni Dinner McLean, VA November 7, 1974, 08/28/1972-11/14/1974 (Box 61, Folder 35)
  - Nobel Symposium [1/2] Spatind, Norway September 9, 1975, 11/19/1975-02/13/1976 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Nobel Symposium [2/2] Spatind, Norway September 9, 1975, 11/29/1974-11/20/1975 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Bohemian Grove San Francisco July 22, 1976, 03/24/1976-09/01/1976 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - NAE Annual Meeting Banquet, 02/06/1976-04/28/1976 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - International Astronautical Federation, 10/10/1976-10/16/1976 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Pacific Telecommunications Conference, 09/14/1976-11/11/1976 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - AIAA Von Karman Lecture [1/3] Washington, DC January 12, 1977, 01/12/1977-03/18/1977 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - AIAA Von Karman Lecture [2/3] Washington, DC January 12, 1977, 01/10/1977-07/07/1977 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - AIAA Von Karman Lecture [3/3] Washington, DC January 12, 1977, 05/11/1961-02/01/1977 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Symposium Civilian/Military Inst. Colorado Springs February 1977, 11/09/1976-01/11/1977 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Conference on North Atlantic Systems Eastborne, England February 14 - 19, 1977, 09/01/1976-03/08/1977 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) Auction Market System Program November 1, 1977, 10/03/1977-11/07/1977 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - AIAA Goddard Astronautics Award February 9, 1978, 09/23/1977-04/05/1978 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Communication Networks 80 Technology of the 1980's Regulatory Aspects January 28, 1980 Washington, DC, 12/21/1979-02/27/1980 (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - West Virginia National Youth Science Camp July 22, 1981 Dirksen Senate Office Building, 07/21/1981-08/13/1981 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Sixth International Conference on Digital Satellite Communications Fall of 1983, 03/31/1981-09/23/1983 (Box 62, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1961-1985; MS2137 Series 4; 8 Linear feet (Box 81, Box 82, Box 83, Box 77, Box 78, Box 79, Box 86, Box 80, Box 85, Box 73, Box 84, Box 74, Box 71, Box 75, Box 72, Box 76)
  This series contains invitations and correspondence. This material dates from 1961-85. This business correspondence was created or received by Joseph V. Charyk and includes letters and memos related to internal matters related to the corporation such as finance and personnel and also correspondence with outside businesses working with COMSAT.
  - Invitations 1966, 02/04/1966-12/17/1966 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Invitations 1967 [1/2], 10/16/1961-05/03/1967 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Invitations 1967 [2/2], 05/04/1967-11/24/1967 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Invitations 1968 [1/2], 01/11/1968-08/04/1968 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Invitations 1968 [2/2], 08/16/1968-12/24/1968 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Invitations 1969 [1/2], 01/16/1969-04/03/1969 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Invitations 1969 [2/2], 04/08/1969-12/22/1969 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Invitations 1970, 01/05/1970-11/24/1970 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Invitations 1973 [1/2], 09/29/1972-05/04/1973 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Invitations 1073 [2/2], 05/17/1973-11/26/1973 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Invitations 1974 [1/2], 06/13/1974-12/30/1974 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Invitations 1974 [2/2], 01/04/1974-06/04/1974 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Speaking Invitations 1964-1965 [1/2], 01/03/1964-09/10/1965 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Speaking Invitations 1964-1965 [2/2], 09/20/1965-12/30/1965 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Speaking Invitations 1966 [1/2], 05/18/1966-10/24/1967 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Speaking Invitations 1966 [2/2], 12/20/1965-04/05/1966 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Speaking Invitations 1967-1968, 02/16/1967-11/21/1968 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Speaking Invitations 1969-1970, 02/18/1969-09/29/1970 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Speaking Invitations 1971, 01/04/1971-08/09/1971 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence 1967-1968, 04/19/1967-09/11/1968 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence 1968-1969, 12/20/1967-11/17/1969 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Directors Correspondence 1969-1970, 05/23/1969-04/10/1970 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence 1970, 01/06/1970-12/31/1970 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence 1971, 01/08/1971-11/06/1971 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous [correspondence] 1971 [1/2], 08/20/1971-12/16/1971 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous [correspondence] 1971 [2/2], 05/28/1971-08/10/1971 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Administration 1972, 03/29/1972-07/20/1972 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence 1972, 02/09/1972-12/29/1972 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence 1973 [1/3], 01/05/1973-04/30/1973 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence 1973 [2/3], 05/03/1973-06/28/1973 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence 1973 [3/3], 07/09/1973-12/27/1973 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence 1974 [1/2], 01/17/1974-04/08/1074 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence 1974 [2/2], 04/09/1974-12/03/1974 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence 1975 [1/2], 01/06/1975-04/29/1975 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence 1975 [2/2], 05/23/1975-12/11/1975 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous [correspondence], 06/11/1979 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Background Briefing Book Oct. 5, 1981 Earthstar, 11/16/1979-10/21/1981 (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Charyk Testimony July 23, 1981 Earthstar, 07/23/1981 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Earthstar Correspondence 1981 Congressional and Governmental Relations Corporate Affairs [1/2], 06/24/1981-12/18/1981 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Earthstar Correspondence 1981 Congressional and Governmental Relations Corporate Affairs [2/2], 03/18/1981 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence 1981 General Services [1/2], 04/08/1981-12/01/1981 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence 1981 General Services [2/2], 01/21/1981-04/21/1981 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence January-March 1982 Personnel [1/2], 02/22/1982-03/31/1982 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence January-March 1982 Personnel [2/2], 01/06/1982-02/22/1982 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence April-June 1982 Personnel, 04/01/1982-06/30/1982 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence July-Sept 1982 Personnel, 07/09/1982-09/28/1982 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence Oct-Dec 1982 Personnel, 10/01/1982-12/23/1982 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Earthstar Correspondence 1982 Congressional and Governmental Relations Corporate Affairs [1/2], 07/14/1982-12/16/1982 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Earthstar Correspondence 1982 Congressional and Governmental Relations Corporate Affairs [2/2], 01/06/1982-07/29/1982 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - FCC General Correspondence 1982 Congressional and Governmental Relations Corporate Affairs, 01/06/1982-12/29/1982 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence 1982 Congressional and Governmental Affairs Corporate Affairs [1/2], 07/30/1982-03/14/1982 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence 1982 Congressional and Governmental Affairs Corporate Affairs, 05/03/1982-12/29/1982 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence 1981-1985 Corporate Development, 10/19/1981-05/13/1985 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence 1982 COMSAT Board of Directors Corporate Secretary [1/2], 06/07/1982-01/04/1983 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence 1982 COMSAT Board of Directors Corporate Secretary [2/2], 01/08/1982-05/27/1983 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence 1982 COMSAT General Corporation, 01/27/1982-12/20/1982 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence 1982 COMSAT General Integrated Systems, Inc COMSAT General Corporation, 01/07/1982-09/14/1982 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence 1982 Environmental Research and Technology, Inc., 02/04/1982-10/20/1982 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence Jan-March 1982 Finance, 12/15/1981-03/29/1982 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence April-June 1982 Finance, 04/08/1982-06/18/1982 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence July-Sept 1982 Finance, 07/01/1982-11/01/1982 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence October-Dec. 1982 Finance, 10/07/1982-12/22/1982 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence 1982 General Counsel, 04/22/1982-11/29/1982 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence 1982 General Services, 01/25/1982-11/18/1982 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence 1982 INMARSAT International Organizations, 04/07/1982-12/30/1982 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence 1982 INTELSAT, 01/19/1982-11/30/1982 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence Jan-May 1982 International Communcations Services COMSAT World Systems Division, 01/05/1982-05/27/1982 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence June-Sept 1982 International Communcations Services COMSAT World Systems Division [1/2], 08/27/1982-09/28/1982 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence June-Sept 1982 International Communcations Services COMSAT World Systems Division [2/2], 06/26/1981-08/19/1982 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence Oct-Dec 1982 International Communications Services, 10/04/1982-12/31/1982 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence 1982 Promotion and Advertising; Corporate Affairs [1/2], 05/14/1982-12/27/1982 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence 1982 Promotion and Advertising; Corporate Affairs [2/2], 01/07/1982-05/12/1982 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence 1982 Research and Development COMSAT World Systems Division, 03/02/1982-12/09/1982 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence Jan-June 1982 Satellite Business Systems, 01/05/1982-06/21/1982 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence July-Dec 1982 Satellite Business Systems [1/2], 12/08/1982-12/20/1982 (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence July-Dec 1982 Satellite Business Systems [2/2], 07/14/1982-11/24/1982 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence Jan-March 1982 Satellite Television Corporation, 01/04/1982-03/26/1982 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence April-June 1982 Satellite Television Corporation, 04/05/1982-06/29/1982 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - General Conference 1982 World Systems Division, 01/19/1982-12/02/1982 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - [Miscellaneous Correspondence 1983], 02/28/1983-12/16/1983 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence Jan-March 1983 Personnel [1/2], 03/28/1984-12/1985 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence Jan-March 1983 Personnel [2/2], 01/02/1983-03/28/1984 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - COMSAT Board of Directors 1983 General Correspondence, 01/17/1983-12/20/1983 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence 1983-1985 Congressional and Government Affairs [1/2], 09/30/1983-08/07/1985 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence 1983-1985 Congressional and Government Affairs [2/2], 01/03/1983-10/23/1984 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Earthstar Correspondence 1983 Congressional and Governmental Relations, 01/03/1983-09/21/1984 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - FCC General Correspondence 1983 Congressional and Governmental Relations, 01/04/1983-03/30/1984 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence 1983-1984 COMSAT General Corporation, 01/13/1983-08/26/1985 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence 1983 Environmental Research and Technology, Inc., 09/30/1983-04/27/1984 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence 1983 Finance, 01/03/1983-12/29/1983 (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence 1983 General Counsel, 11/08/1983-01/31/1985 (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence 1983 General Services, 12/21/1983-04/15/1985 (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence 1983 Promotion and Advertising, 01/20/1983-03/12/1984 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence 1983 Research and Development, 01/10/1983-02/01/1985 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence 1983 Satellite Business Systems [1/3], undated (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence 1983 Satellite Business Systems [2/3], undated (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence 1983 Satellite Business Systems [3/3], undated (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence Jan-March 1983 Satellite Television Corporation [1/4], 12/19/1983-04/22/1985 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence Jan-March 1983 Satellite Television Corporation [2/4], 09/09/1983-12/23/1983 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence Jan-March 1983 Satellite Television Corporation [3/4], 06/30/1983-10/27/1983 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence Jan-March 1983 Satellite Television Corporation [4/4], 11/12/1981-06/14/1983 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence 1984 Finance, 07/06/1983-05/21/1985 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence COMSAT Board of Directors 1984, 07/28/1983-08/30/1985 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence 1983 INTELSAT [1/2], 12/15/1983-04/12/1985 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence 1983 INTELSAT [2/2], 03/01/1983-12/02/1983 (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous INTELSAT/INMARSAT, 01/10/1983-03/07/1985 (Box 86, Folder 4)
- Speeches, 1963-1985; MS2137 Series 5; 3 Linear feet (Box 63, Box 64)
  This series contains speeches, notes, and slides. This material dates from 1963-85.
  - Major Addresses by Dr. Joseph V. Charyk #23 - 29, 05/22/1967-11/12/1968 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Major Addresses by Joseph V. Charyk #30 - 37, 11/14/1968-12/17/1969 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Major Addresses by Joseph V. Charyk #38 - 43, 01/08/1970-10/23/1970 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Major Addresses by Joseph V. Charyk #44 - 51, 05/30/1971-06/01/1973 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Informal Remarks [1/2] Earth Station Dedications Magazine Articles, etc., 07/18/1963-10/11/1971 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Informal Remarks [2/2] Earth Stations Magazine Articles, etc., 10/29/1971-12/23/1975 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Yale - Princeten Luncheon April 29, 1965, 12/14/1964-04/29/1965 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Speeches and Articles of Interest [1/2], 09/25/1964-10/24/1967 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Speeches and Articles of Interest [2/2], 12/01/1967-11/04/1969 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Speeches 1963 - 1976, 07/1963-06/21/1976 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Remarks Emmy Award Dinner, 11/25/1974 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Speech at M.I.T. November 15, 1976, 08/07/1973-11/15/1976 (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Speech "Eyeing the 80's" Loma, Atlanta March 14, 1977, 10/15/1976-03/22/1977 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Speech "Communications... through a Regulator Thicket" (MIT) 3/14/1978, 11/14/1972-03/20/1978 (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Speeches Marconi 75th Anniversary January 18, 1978, 01/18/1978-01/30/1978 (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - DeForest Audion Award Speech May 20, 1978 NYC, 04/27/1978-06/12/1978 (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Speech Impact of Satellites on World Communications June 20, 1978, 06/20/1978 (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Speeches 1978 - 1981, 07/1978-09/22/1981 (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - New York Society of Security Analysts [1/2] July 11, 1979 New York, New York, 03/03/1978-08/09/1979 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - New York Society of Security Analysts [2/2] July 11, 1979 New York, New York, 07/03/1979-07/11/1979 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Speeches 1970 - 1980, 01/08/1970-09/22/1980 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Boston Security Analysts Society, Inc. October 6, 1980, 01/03/1980-10/06/1980 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Ferris Washington Showcase September 22, 1980, 09/17/1980-10/01/1980 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - A Presidential Classroom for Young Americans March 6, 1981, 01/07/1981-03/05/1981 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - EASCON '81 Keynote Address More Capacity in Orbit, More uses on Earth Satellite Communications, The Broad View, 11/03/1981-11/17/1981 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Leeds Castle Tabin Foundation March 27 - 30, 1982, 01/18/1981-11/02/1982 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - ITU Plenipotentiary Conference Nairobi September 28 - November, 1982 COMSAT World Systems Division, 12/17/1981-11/08/1982 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - National Press Club Speech, 05/04/1983-06/23/1983 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - George Washington University March 16, 1983, undated (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Slides J.V. Chark's Speech November 1984 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Speech Material [1/4], 09/08/1964-01/08/1976 (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Speech Material [2/4], 04/28/1976-12/02/1984 (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Speech Material [3/4], 08/1977-12/02/1983 (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - Speech Material [4/4], 02/06/1984-06/27/1985 (Box 64, Folder 16)